<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/protein-folding/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2021-05-21T08:27:10+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/protein-folding/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Ramit Surana | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Ramit Surana Personal Blog</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Understanding Protein Folding</title>
      <link href="/protein-folding" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding Protein Folding" />
      <published>2021-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/protein-folding</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/protein-folding">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-protein-folding&quot;&gt;What is Protein Folding?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When you order a protein from the chinese place, it is linear, like spaghetti, so you must fold it to make it in the shape you want. Folding protein is when you bend it to create the shape you want. The shape of your protein affects how it acts, and how it interacts with other proteins. If you want to be a good protein folder, you must practice, and be able to fold all the different shapes that proteins might need to be in. There are many different shapes that you can fold it into, such as a hairpin, a cloverleaf, a Z fold, a hairpin with extra bits sticking out, a jellyfish, a braid, and many more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Protein folding is an important skill, as it is used in many different ways. Many proteins are used for structural support, like the keratin in your hair and nails, and collagen in your skin. Another purpose of proteins is to transport other molecules around your body, like hemoglobin. They are also the catalysts that help other chemical reactions go faster, like enzymes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;components-of-the-cell-membrane-and-the-cell-wall&quot;&gt;Components of the cell membrane, and the cell wall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The cell membrane is a very important part of the cell. It keeps the cell alive. The membrane is made up of a phospholipid bilayer. It also has proteins embedded into it. The proteins on the membrane are either transmembrane proteins, or peripheral proteins. Membrane transporters are used to transport molecules across the membrane. If you have a protein that is a transmembrane protein, it means that it is embedded in the membrane, and has a hydrophobic side and a hydrophilic side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Membrane transporters are able to transport molecules across the membrane, because they have a hydrophobic side and a hydrophilic side. Some proteins are peripheral proteins, which means that they are not embedded in the membrane, but they are outside of it. The cell wall is the part of the cell that holds the cell up and gives it its structure. It is made up of cellulose, and is a very sturdy material. People use cellulose in things like paper and wood, and it is very strong. Cellulose is a polysaccharide, or sugar polymer. Cellulose is a linear polymer, which means that it is made up of only one type of sugar, glucose. Polysaccharides are big, long, and unbranched chains of glucose molecules. Cellulose is especially long, as it has a very high degree of polymerization. The number of glucose molecules in cellulose is counted in the hundreds of thousands. Cellulose is a very important part of the cell, as it holds the cell up, and gives it shape.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;structure-of-protein&quot;&gt;Structure of Protein&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main idea in this process is to put the protein in a situation that destabilizes the unfolded state. This can be accomplished by means of disulfide bond formation. The protein is engineered to contain cysteine residues at strategic positions. The protein is allowed to fold in vitro. The protein is then incubated in the presence of a reducing agent that forces the disulfide bonds to form. The result is a protein that folds autonomously in a test tube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proteins are made up of amino acids linked together by peptide bonds. The amino acids are linked together in a linear fashion. The linear protein is coiled into a three-dimensional structure. The structure is stabilized by noncovalent interactions. These interactions include hydrogen bonds, nonpolar interactions, electrostatic interactions, and hydrophobic interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proteins are very large molecules. To understand how they fold, it is helpful to think of the process in terms of a polymer. The polymer chain is folded in a way that minimizes the free energy of the system. The chain is also folded so that the hydrophobic amino acids are in the interior region of the protein and the hydrophilic amino acids are on the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strength-of-protein-folds&quot;&gt;Strength of Protein Folds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that the folding of proteins is not as simple as the folding of a polymer. The hydrophobic interactions between hydrophobic amino acids are quite strong and do not completely dissociate even when the protein is folded. The hydrophobic interactions are balanced by van der Waals interactions between the exposed hydrophilic amino acids and the surrounding solvent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interactions between the amino acids are more than simple covalent bonds. The bond strength and the orientation are dependent on the local environment. The interactions between the alpha carbon of one amino acid and the alpha carbon of the next amino acid are much stronger than the interactions between the side chains.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>ramitsurana</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="[&quot;cell wall&quot;, &quot;protein structures&quot;, &quot;peptide bonds&quot;]" />
      

      
        <category term="protein folding" />
      
        <category term="molecules" />
      
        <category term="cell wall" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">How Protein Folding Works?</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
